CHRISTIAN JULIAN LIENDO

EMAIL: cjl248@cornell.edu | PHONE: (646) 338 - 0622

LinkedIn | GitHub | Medium

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Software Engineer, experienced in Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, and React with a dual B.A. in Information Science and Economics. I discovered web development as an undergrad but truly became passionate about it while working as a technical recruiter. Many personal projects and technical meetups later, I committed to a career change. As a recent graduate of Flatiron School's Software Engineering program, I am currently fully focused on launching my career as a fullstack web developer.

SKILLS

- Technical: JavaScript (ES6, D3.js, jQuery.js), React.js, Redux.js, Node.js, Ruby, Rails, Java, Python, Android Studio, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, GitHub, Bash, HTML5/CSS3, Sass, Material-UI, Semantic UI, MVC, ORM, RESTful API Development, TDD, BDD, Discrete Structures, Natural Language Processing, Regression Analysis (STATA, MATLAB)
- Languages: English, Spanish, Italian

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Clarity - Frontend | Backend

A mindfulness hub (React, Rails API, PostgreSQL, Fullstack Auth using bcrypt and JWT)

- Integrated functional Material-UI React components and hooks to create a responsive lightweight user experience
- Levered 3 external APIs including the YouTube API to create an immersive, highly customizable user experience

RoomFellows - Frontend | Backend

A relationship management system (React, Rails API, PostgreSQL, Fullstack Auth using bcrypt and JWT)

- Designed reusable React components and integrated Semantic UI styling with React Router for scalability
- Implemented inversion of control principles in React component hierarchy to reverse data flow, update state, and trigger
 optimistic re-rendering for an engaging user experience

Catstagram - GitHub

Remake of Yelp and Instagram (JavaScript-ES6, JSON, AJAX, Rails API, PostgreSQL)

- Developed a RESTful Rails API and serialized JSON from a PostgreSQL database to respond to frontend Fetch API requests
- Implemented delegation to apply event bubbling and allow for dynamic DOM manipulation in response to user interaction

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Software Engineer, New York, NY

Nov 2019 - Present

- Calabria Pizza: redesigned a fullstack SPA with fullstack auth and admin dashboard according to client feature specifications
- Riskly (Rails API, JavaScript, React): a fullstack web app that investigates the correlation between different factors and risk of infection with SARS-CoV-2

Axelon Services Corporation, New York, NY

Feb 2018 - Jan 2019

Technical Recruiter

- Successfully recruited for various technical positions such as Software Engineers (frontend, backend, fullstack, big data, microservices, mobile), DevOps Engineers, Cloud Architects, Scrum Masters and IT Security Experts
- Responsible for high-volume cold calling, screening, interviewing and coaching qualified candidates through the hiring process using the internal ATS JobDiva, and various VMSes.

Tutors on Wheels, Astoria, NY

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

Private Tutoring Manager

Jun 2016 - Dec 2017

- More than tripled the number of active private tutors from 10 to 31 including MA and PhD educated teachers through an aggressive hiring plan based on unique client needs
- Acquired and retained new clients across all subjects and grade levels by assigning educators to uniquely fit student needs, learning styles and goals

Tutor (SAT, SHSAT, Regents)

Jan 2016 - May 2016

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY

Oct 2019

Software Engineering Immersive Program

Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

May 2015

B.A. Information Science

B.A. Economics

• Relevant Coursework: Intro to Computing using Python, Object-Oriented Programming and Data Structures, Data-Driven Web Applications, Intro to Natural Language Processing, Discrete Structures, Networks II, Designing Technology for Social Impact